## POREDDY SUDHEER KUMAR REDDY

Email: <u>sudhiir43@outlook.com</u>

Mobile: 9640673259

**Linkedin** 

#### **PROFILE**

Data Scientist with 4+ years of experience in python, R, SQL, Flask. Developed end-to-end machine learning models, Built Flask APIs to publish machine learning models. Worked on web scraping for data collection. Developed prototypes for medical image classification with deep learning.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Mar 2021present

## **Analyst, Deloitte**

Working on automating clinical trials report using machine learning classification and data

engineering

Responsible for Data wrangling, Model building

Used Python, AWS Lambda, Machine Learning, SQL

## Dec 2020-Mar 2021

## Data Analyst, Geoiq.io

Worked on various projects including Web scraping, Geo spatial analytics and predictive

analytics

Responsible for Data collection from various sites using web scraping, Processing,

aggregating and storing data

Used Python, SQL, Web scraping

# Mar 2018-May 2020

## **Data Scientist, Brontobyte Analytics**

Worked on various projects including Retail Analytics, Machine Learning, Predictive

Analytics, chatbots, Deep learning for computer vision

Responsible for Data collection, preprocessing, model building, model validation and

model deployment using API

Used Python, R, SQL, Python machine learning and deep learning libraries and Flask

## Sep 2017- Data Science Research Intern, Tech Mahindra

Nov 2017 Worked on customer behavior analytics for an Online Education Tech company

Used various machine learning techniques including Logistic Regression, Linear

Regression and Forecasting to predict the user turn-out probability and future revenue

generation

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Python, R, SQL
- Machine Learning, Deep Learning
- Flask, Web scraping
- Probability and statistics

#### **ACHEIVEMENTS**

- INSOFE scholarship for being one of the top performers in the course.
- Secured Rank 1 in Monsoon Credit Tech Hiring Hackathon.
- Organized first international triangular cricket series for physically challenged.

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Retail Analytics**

- Aim is to Segment and Score customers based on the purchase patterns for a retail client to design customer specific promotions
- Used clustering to segment customers based on their purchasing patterns
- Used a mixed model of Linear and Logistic Regression to assign score to each unique customer
- Techniques used: Clustering, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Forecasting, Association Rules

## Mammogram Image Classification

- Aim is to classify the mammography images as Benign or Malignant
- To help radiologists to make better and quick decisions
- Techniques: CNN, transfer learning, Autoencoders, Gradcam
- Tool: Python, Keras, Deep Learning

## Production Optimization

- Objective of the project is to reduce the wastage of beverage bottles produced in Hindustan Coca-Cola Beverages
- Techniques used: Statistical T-test, Flask

#### **EDUCATION**

## 2017: PGP in Data Science

INSOFE, Hyderabad

Trained extensively on on Various machine learning and deep learning techniques like Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, KNN, Decision Trees, Random Forests, Gradient Boosting, Clustering, Association Rules, MLP, CNN, RNN and Probability and Statistics.

Received a scholarship for being one of the top performers in the course

## 2012-2016: B.Tech Mechanical Engineering

TKR College of Engineering and Technology